WILL KNOWLES

Olathe, KS 66061

Phone: 615-707-0495 | Email: will@willknowles.com

LinkedIn: linkedIn: linkedin.com/in/willknowles | GitHub: github.com/wfknowles | Portfolio: wfknowles.github.io

SUMMARY

Web developer with experience in multiple languages, libraries, and frameworks. Equal parts creative and detail-oriented, with a hunger for challenges and a passion for learning. Capable of handling multiple projects in a deadline driven environment working independently or collaboratively with a team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP, Ruby, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, jQuery, Bootstrap, Foundation, React, GraphQL, Sequelize, Mongoose, Ruby on Rails, Node.js, Git, AWS, Heroku, Webpack, PWAs, Wordpress, and Adobe Creative Suite.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Director of Marketing & Technology Docs Who Care

2017 – 2020

Olathe, KS

- Responsible for organizing, designing, and executing marketing campaigns along with sales and marketing collateral.
- Responsible for maintaining IT infrastructure and providing technical support for the employee base.
- Architected and developed a Ruby on Rails business management software that merged and extended two pre-existing applications' functionality and data storage.

Marketing & Technology Consultant Freelance

2016 - 2017

Nashville, TN

- Designed and developed marketing websites for clients.
 - Implemented sales funnels that integrated with customer CRMs for tracking and managing marketing automation.
 - Implemented educational portal integrated with customer CRM for tracking and managing user authentication and content management.
- Implemented customer experience protocols, template responses, and management system.

Chief Experience Officer: Product Designer, Marketing, CX DonorLynk

2015 – 2016

Nashville, TN

- Designed and managed the development of a web-based non-profit fundraising product.
- Built and managed the marketing and customer experience teams to support sales and customer onboarding.
- Provided consultative sales to non-profit organizations to implement web products, database customizations, and data migrations.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Designer, Fabricator, Developer Good Craft Company, LLC

2020 - 2021

Olathe, KS

- Designed, researched, and developed the "lightbox," a customizable, built-to-order LED lamp.
- Developed and implemented a production operation to utilize unskilled labor.
- Architected and implemented an online ordering and fulfillment management system.

- Photographer/Videographer
 - Prospected and sold varying types of photo and video services to clients in and around the Nashville market.
- First Photo-Assistant
 - Coordinated with photographers to establish gear and labor requirements necessary for production.
 - Provided creative and technical problem-solving to help achieve the photographers' vision within budgetary and creative constraints.
 - Managed gear and labor on shoot days to maintain a safe, organized, and successful production.
- Assistant Video Editor/Digital Imaging Technician
 - Captured, digitized, and logged shot media from multiple camera systems during studio/shoot days.
 - Prepared and organized media within episode workfiles throughout post-production.
 - Digitized and rendered final media files per broadcast standard.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate: University of Kansas - Olathe, KS Bachelor's Degree in Psychology: Trevecca Nazarene University - Nashville, TN High School Diploma: Chattanooga State Middle College High School - Chattanooga, TN